<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xml:base="https://www.unl.edu/newp/rss.xml" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RSS</title>
    <link>https://www.unl.edu/newp/rss.xml</link>
    <description></description>
    <language>en</language>
     <atom:link href="https://www.unl.edu/newp/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/newp/2018-agate-writers-workshop&quot;&gt;2018 Agate Writer’s Workshop – Women of the West: Strength in the Nebraska Panhandle&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>https://www.unl.edu/newp/newp/2018-agate-writers-workshop</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Spring is here! And so is your invitation to carve away some time to be creative and re-energize this summer at the Agate Fossil Beds National Monument Teachers Writing Workshop and Writing Marathon this summer, July 16 – 18, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Exploring the Women of the West: Strength in the Nebraska Panhandle” marks the third year the Monument is collaborating with the Nebraska Writing Project to offer teachers of all disciplines and grade levels the opportunity to learn new strategies to integrate science, language arts, and social studies with writing. Workshop participants will not only delve into the many resources of Agate Fossil Beds, but also at select sites on the Pine Ridge Reservation and at Fort Robinson State Park. Workshop registration closes on June 30th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teacher participants of the 2018 Agate Teacher Writing Workshop will be immersed in place-based writing exercises, readings, and discussions. In “Exploring the Women of the West: Strength in the Nebraska Panhandle,” participants will uncover in the history of Agate through the women of the late 1800-1900s. Participants will explore paleontology from women’s perspectives—both historic and modern; discover the voice of an African American woman in the Nebraska Panhandle in the 1880s; learn from Lakota women and their art; and consider the contributions of the women of the Agate Springs Ranch, the land from which this national park unit originated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Past participants have come from every corner of Nebraska for this opportunity to network and share their ideas about cross-curricular writing. All have left with a rich sense of writing through place, science and history.&lt;/p&gt;
Scheduled Talks

“Paleontology: A Woman’s Perspective”by Ellen Stepleton, a retired fossil preparator from the University of Nebraska State Museum (confirmed)
“Octavia Reeves, an African American woman in the Nebraska panhandle in the 1880s”by Holly Counts, an independent historian (confirmed)
“American Indian Women and their art” by Audrey Jacobs, museum educator, Red Cloud Indian School Heritage Center (confirmed)
“The contributions of women ranchers” by Gretchen Meade, great-granddaughter of Agate homesteader James Cook and the granddaughter of paleontologist, geologist, and writer Harold Cook (confirmed)
“Agate museum collection and artifacts” by Maryann Neubert, NPS museum curator (confirmed)

Scheduled Activities

A ranger-led tour of Agate Fossil Beds National Monument, including of the Red Cloud artifacts in the park’s museum collection
A tour of the The Heritage Center at the Red Cloud Indian School in Pine Ridge, SD
Access to primary sources from the Agate Fossil Beds National Monument museum collections
Visits to the Fort Robinson State Park, including site of the Red Cloud Indian Agency
A Monday evening cookout with National Park Service rangers and staff

Workshop Information
&lt;p&gt;Registration is available through June 30th at &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/21pj1p&quot;&gt;https://goo.gl/21pj1p&lt;/a&gt; or by contacting Jan Knispel at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jknispel@gmail.com&quot;&gt;jknispel@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Dates
&lt;p&gt;July 16-18th&lt;/p&gt;
Cost
&lt;p&gt;$75&lt;/p&gt;
Accomodations
&lt;p&gt;Participants will need to make their own lodging accommodations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accommodations can be made at:&lt;/p&gt;

the Sage Motel (&lt;a href=&quot;http://sagemotelharrison.com/&quot;&gt;http://sagemotelharrison.com/&lt;/a&gt;) in Harrison, NE (the community nearest the park)
the Quivey House Bed and Breakfast in Mitchell, NE
Comfort Inn, Days Inn, Hampton Inn and Suites, Holiday Inn Express, Monument Inn and Suites, or other hotels in Scottsbluff and Gering, NE
Fort Robinson State Park in Crawford, NE (Nebraska Game and Parks Commission)
Tent and RV campsites outside of the park (&lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/mkL49P&quot;&gt;https://goo.gl/mkL49P&lt;/a&gt;). Refrigeration is available at the park for those tent camping.

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to split the cost of a room with a roommate, please choose the option at this registration link, and you will be connected with another teacher to make arrangements. Questions about accommodations can directed to Alvis Mar at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:alvis_mar@nps.gov&quot;&gt;alvis_mar@nps.gov&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
Register
&lt;p&gt;For additional information, access the workshop brochure here &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/RkNwqm&quot;&gt;https://goo.gl/RkNwqm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To register for the workshop, complete and submit the online application at &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/yGfG8C&quot;&gt;https://goo.gl/yGfG8C&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also contact Park Ranger Alvis Mar, (308) 665-4110, &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:alvis_mar@nps.gov&quot;&gt;alvis_mar@nps.gov&lt;/a&gt;, or Jan Knispel, &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jknispel@gmail.com&quot;&gt;jknispel@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; for more information&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“By examining, reflecting upon and analyzing through writing the contributions of the uncelebrated—yet phenomenal—women of this remarkable landscape, teachers can create learning opportunities for their students that will lead them to better understand the factors that have molded our nation’s collective heritage. What better place than a national park–like Agate Fossil Beds National Monument– to find those lessons and revelations?” – James Hill, Agate Fossil Beds Park Superintendent James Hill&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Wednesday, March 28, 2018 - 13:05</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Diana Weis</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">78000</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/newp/speed-geeking-networking-professional-development-event-neta&quot;&gt;Speed Geeking! Networking &amp;amp; Professional Development Event @ NETA&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>https://www.unl.edu/newp/newp/speed-geeking-networking-professional-development-event-neta</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Please join the Nebraska Writing Project at NETA!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday, April 19, from 5:00-5:45 Room 208 of CenturyLink Center&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are hosting a fun networking and professional development event following NETA Day 1 entitled &amp;#8220;Speed Geeking!&amp;#8221;&lt;br /&gt;
Connect with fellow educators who are passionate about using writing and technology together. Anyone can&lt;br /&gt;
get up and “geek out” about the ways they use technology with their students. Think speed dating, but with&lt;br /&gt;
cool tech projects!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each participant gets 5 minutes or less to present their tech idea. We’ll provide the projector, connections, and&lt;br /&gt;
speakers. The more, the merrier at this high-energy event! If you’re interested, come on by room 208 of&lt;br /&gt;
CenturyLink after the final session of NETA Day 1! The event will be hosted by NeWP board members Jennifer&lt;br /&gt;
Troester of O’Neill High School and Melissa Legate of Pierce High School.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Thursday, March 1, 2018 - 13:53</pubDate>
 <dc:creator />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">78001</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/newp/invitation-to-the-2018-neta-spring-conference&quot;&gt;Invitation to the 2018 NETA Spring Conference&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>https://www.unl.edu/newp/newp/invitation-to-the-2018-neta-spring-conference</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of our partnership with the Nebraska Educational Technology Association, we’re happy to invite you to join us at the 2018 NETA Spring Conference, April 18-20th at the CenturyLink Center in Omaha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you and your school receive from attending the 2018 NETA Spring Conference:&lt;/p&gt;

Over 200+ featured, breakout, and interactive educational technology sessions from which to choose
Numerous hands-on workshops designed to give you a more in-depth experience
Nationally recognized speakers
Admittance to an Innovation Lab
Playgrounds to personally experience the newest technologies
Opportunity to meet and interact with over 100 exhibitors
Networking opportunities to expand your professional learning network to continue learning throughout the year

&lt;p&gt;Take advantage of Early Bird Registration pricing before March 16, 2018 and register a group of 10 or more attendees to receive a discount on each registration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information or to register, visit the &lt;a href=&quot;http://netasite.org/?page_id=4334&quot;&gt;NETA website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Monday, February 5, 2018 - 12:17</pubDate>
 <dc:creator />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">77999</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/newp/newp-spring-and-summer-writing-marathons&quot;&gt;NeWP Spring and Summer Writing Marathons&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>https://www.unl.edu/newp/newp/newp-spring-and-summer-writing-marathons</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing Marathons have always held a special place within the NeWP community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Nebraska Writing Project has been sponsoring writing marathons since 2006, embracing their ability to bring teachers back to their NeWP roots and to promote place-conscious thinking and writing. Seasonal writing marathons are held each year. This year the spring marathon was held in partnership with the Omaha Warrior Writers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NeWP TCs and members of the Omaha Warrior Writers met at Sorenson Library in early June to launch the 2017 Spring Writing Marathon. Writing groups set out across the Dundee neighborhood to capture the day through their pens. Popular writing spots included eCreamery, Memorial Park, the Dundee community garden, and local coffee shops. Please enjoy some of our writing from the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NeWP TCs and members of the Omaha Warrior Writers met at Sorenson Library in early June to launch the 2017 Spring Writing Marathon. Writing groups set out across the Dundee neighborhood to capture the day through their pens. Popular writing spots included eCreamery, Memorial Park, the Dundee community garden, and local coffee shops. Please enjoy some of our writing from the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NeWP TCs and members of the Omaha Warrior Writers met at Sorenson Library in early June to launch the 2017 Spring Writing Marathon. Writing groups set out across the Dundee neighborhood to capture the day through their pens. Popular writing spots included eCreamery, Memorial Park, the Dundee community garden, and local coffee shops. Please enjoy some of our writing from the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The summer marathon was held at the NeWP board retreat at the St. Benedictine Retreat Center located North of Schuyler. Several groups ventured out within the monastery and the city of Schuyler. Participant writing from both events are available through the following links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://spark.adobe.com/page/8NnXnM48aKSwR/&quot;&gt;Spring Warrior Writer Marathon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://spark.adobe.com/page/bcju9Il7hxN4n/&quot;&gt;Summer Board Writing Marathon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our next marathon will be the Platte River State Writing Marathon on September 9th. This is held in conjunction with the NeWP UnConference (Saturday, Sept. 10th @9:00AM) and Platte River State Writing Retreat (Sept. 8-10th). For more Information about these events see the event posting on Facebook or email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:dweis@cox.net&quot;&gt;dweis@cox.net&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Monday, July 31, 2017 - 13:44</pubDate>
 <dc:creator />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">77996</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/newp/agate-writer%E2%80%99s-workshop-to-be-held-july-17-19-2017&quot;&gt;Agate Writer’s Workshop to be held July 17-19, 2017&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>https://www.unl.edu/newp/newp/agate-writer%25E2%2580%2599s-workshop-to-be-held-july-17-19-2017</link>
    <description>This year&amp;#8217;s Agate Writer&amp;#8217;s Workshop will be July 17-19th at Agate Fossil Beds National Monument.  We will explore the Women of the West with focus on the women scientists, paleontologists and homesteaders that built the communities and resources in Western Nebraska.  Please join this unique event by &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/yGfG8C&quot;&gt;registering online&lt;/a&gt; and extend the invitation to interested educators from other disciplines.

&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unl.edu/newp/Docs/2017agatewritersworkshop.pdf&quot;&gt;Download this year&amp;#8217;s flier for more&lt;/a&gt; details.


Exploring the Bones of Place: 50 Years in the Nebraska Panhandle
&lt;p&gt;Spend two days at Agate Fossil Beds National Monument discovering the bones of place. Staff from the National Park Service and Nebraska Writing Project will lead teachers through a variety of activities designed to make science exciting, inviting and accessible through writing. This workshop is open to teachers of all grade levels and content areas. Participants can expect to:&lt;/p&gt;

generate their own creative writing
explore the women of Agate and their unique roles in paleontology, geology, and place
leave with classroom activities for integrating science and writing

&lt;p&gt;Registration fee for the program is $75. The workshop is limited to fifteen participants. It begins at 8:00a.m. on July 17th and concludes at 2:00p.m. on July 19th. Food and lodging are not available at the park. &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScsD4FbBwU4L2xzd8Wn6CPZlJu94O-jn-4SITPAr9Nb-ZEdmQ/viewform&quot;&gt;Registration ends &lt;strong&gt;June 30, 2017&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants will need to arrange for lodging in nearby communities. Local hotel or camping accommodations can be found at:&lt;/p&gt;

Harrison House Hotel in Harrison, NE (www.harrisonhousehotel.com)
Hotels in Scottsbluff/Gering, such as Comfort Inn, Days Inn, Hampton Inn and Suites, Holiday Inn Express
Fort Robinson State Park (Nebraska Games and Parks Commission)

&lt;p&gt;A limited number of tent camping sites are available within Agate. Sites have access to an indoor bathroom and kitchen facilities. Reservations for tenting sites is available on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nps.gov/agfo/index.htm&quot;&gt;Agate Fossil Beds website&lt;/a&gt; or by emailing Alvis Mar at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:alvis_mar@nps.gov&quot;&gt;alvis_mar@nps.gov&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Wednesday, April 26, 2017 - 14:50</pubDate>
 <dc:creator />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">77992</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/newp/2017-eastern-youth-writing-festival&quot;&gt;2017 Eastern Youth Writing Festival&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>https://www.unl.edu/newp/newp/2017-eastern-youth-writing-festival</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;The Nebraska Writing Project held its annual Eastern Youth Writing Festival on April 1st, 2017. This event, designed for students in grades 6-8, was held at Gretna Middle School. A total of 32 students from Elkhorn, Gretna, Bellevue, Fremont, and Wahoo schools attended. While at the event, students were able to participate in three sessions, led by area teachers Theresa Huttman, Patrick White, and Santha Walters. These sessions covered topics such as upcycling song lyrics into poetry, the analysis of film and script writing, and developing superhero characters that are both good and evil. After the sessions, students were able to go on a writing marathon or continue to work on pieces they had begun during the instructional sessions. Some students are working on pieces for publication; these will be available at the end of the month on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://newpyouthwritingfestival.wordpress.com&quot;&gt;Nebraska Writing Project Youth Writing Festival Blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amy Tasich  |  Nebraska Writing Project&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Monday, April 3, 2017 - 14:11</pubDate>
 <dc:creator />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">77991</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/newp/newp-quilt-raffle-tickets-now-available&quot;&gt;NeWP Quilt Raffle Tickets Now Available&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>https://www.unl.edu/newp/newp/newp-quilt-raffle-tickets-now-available</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;The annual Nebraska Writing Project Quilt Raffle is beginning. The NeWP has raffled quilts as a fundraiser at the annual Spring Gathering in May for several years now. Tickets are going on sale now, at the Nebraska Educational Technology Conference on April 20, and 21 in Omaha, NE, and at the Spring Gathering on May 5 in the Colonial Room at the UNL Student Union in Lincoln, NE. The quilt pictured was made from fabric celebrating the honey bee including fabric printed with quotations about bees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are on sale for one dollar a ticket or six tickets for five dollars. Contact Amanda Larabee at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:alarabee2@unl.edu&quot;&gt;alarabee2@unl.edu&lt;/a&gt; for ticket information and purchase.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Monday, March 20, 2017 - 13:36</pubDate>
 <dc:creator />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">77990</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/newp/newp-fall-and-winter-writing-marathons&quot;&gt;NeWP Fall and Winter Writing Marathons&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>https://www.unl.edu/newp/newp/newp-fall-and-winter-writing-marathons</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;The fall and winter marathon were filled with great writers and beautiful weather. The annual fall writing marathon was held at Platte River State Park September 26-28th. Participants gathered Saturday morning for a new addition to the weekend, an Unconference. Veteran and pre-service teachers enjoyed an open discussion on education issues such as the responsibility and restrictions of social justice in the classroom. Ideas were discussed over hot-off-the griddle pancakes and under a light sprinkling of rain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The marathon launched from Owen 9 at noon. Two groups of writers ventured out to explore climbing walls, tipis, the Interstate Chapel and Platte River State Park’s rock wall. Writing was shared along with an impressive cabin dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This years Winter Marathon was preceeded by the NeWP winter board retreat and celebration dinner for Rhonda Schoenmaker. TCs and board members offered special thanks for Rhonda’s support of and dedication to the NeWP and teachers. A poetry tribute highlighted Rhonda’s talent for keeping things running smoothly. Her patience, ingenuity, and warmth was likened to everything from motor oil to being a master gardener.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The winter marathon launched from Blue Orchid. The first stop brought the writers to Gallery 9, an independent gallery and professional artists affiliation. The gallery’s highlight was the main gallery which showcased American Veterans paintings and photography. Afterwards the writers spread out around the Lincoln capital, observing and noting the Women’s March. Indigo Books was home of the final writing and read around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read writing from these two events, please click &lt;a href=&quot;https://spark.adobe.com/page/BzALxTammfyru/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diana Weis  |  Nebraska Writing Project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;asp-embed-link&quot; href=&quot;https://spark.adobe.com/page/BzALxTammfyru/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Tuesday, February 28, 2017 - 13:18</pubDate>
 <dc:creator />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">77987</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/newp/plum-creek-literacy-festival&quot;&gt;Plum Creek Literacy Festival&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>https://www.unl.edu/newp/newp/plum-creek-literacy-festival</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;On Saturday, September 24, 2016, I attended the Plum Creek Literacy Festival at Concordia University in Seward, NE. This, the 3rd day of a 3 day event, was designed for adults to enjoy listening to children&amp;#8217;s authors speak about their writing and their books. While I got to enjoy the funny, engaging, and interesting presentations by numerous authors, I also got to take part in representing the Nebraska Writing Project. Along with 4 other people, I talked with the educators and interested patrons at the conference about NeWP and what it had to offer. We received information from 12 different conference attendees, including people from UNL, Peru State College, York College, and Lincoln City Libraries, as well as a retired teacher. There were also many others who stopped by to ask questions and expressed interest in our mission. It was my first experience representing NeWP at a conference and was an unbelievable opportunity to socialize with others who also have a passion for writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ashley Mundil  |  Pyrtle Elementary, Lincoln&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Friday, February 17, 2017 - 14:52</pubDate>
 <dc:creator />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">77985</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/newp/nine-secondary-teachers-participate-in-the-gretna-writing-project-institute&quot;&gt;Nine Secondary Teachers Participate in the Gretna Writing Project Institute&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>https://www.unl.edu/newp/newp/nine-secondary-teachers-participate-in-the-gretna-writing-project-institute</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;In the Gretna Public School district the practice and teaching of writing is held in high regard. Gretna teachers in all grade levels and across the curriculum have long worked together to discover the best practices in writing instruction and assessment through research, experimentation, and collaboration. The fall of 2016 brought an opportunity for Gretna’s secondary teachers to devote three hours per week in the pursuit of these tasks as participants in the Gretna Writing Project Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gretna has offered an annual embedded writing institute to its k-12 teachers for several years now, but the 2016 class opened the doors to a new territory when three science teachers joined the six English teachers participating in the institute. Together, these nine educators spent invaluable hours discussing the field of teaching and the craft of writing. Though nearly all participants were initially hesitant to enroll in the institute (We all know that the “We teach! There’s never enough time as it is!” argument is a valid one!) each was glad to have done so by the end of the semester.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be impossible to determine which component of the writing institute model is most effective: the EQUIPS, the inquiry projects, or personal writing groups. Each of these facets of the institute inspired lively and heartfelt discussions and helped the teacher participants to unravel their own perspectives on issues facing them professionally and personally. Three small writing groups, made up of three teachers each, were a welcome respite in the hectic shuffle of teaching every week. Personal writing projects that were developed during the institute include poetry collections, a playscript, several chapters of a novel, professional research and writing for journal submission, and even some ancestry chronicling. The relationships formed by sharing these intimate writings with one another are truly priceless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The EQUIP presentations were also brilliantly planned and executed each week. The addition of the science teachers to the traditional institute dynamic created a wonderfully diverse set of voices in the feedback and questioning portion of each presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EQUIP topics included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;em&gt;Un-Writing&lt;/em&gt;: Putting Language to its Best Use
Using Film to Promote Writing
Stream of Consciousness Composition in the Science and English Classroom
Qualitative Analysis and the Use of Imagery in the Chemistry Lab
Authentic Writing Experiences in Every Classroom
Sensory Observation as a Writing Tool
Creative Writing in Science Content
Drawing for Analysis and Poetry Writing
Imitation Writing: &lt;em&gt;The Book of Qualities&lt;/em&gt; and Jue Ju poems

&lt;p&gt;Inquiry presentations were equally diverse and intriguing, featuring research and discussion about multiple intelligences, the brain science behind listening to music while studying and writing, and changing the idea of literature studies to feature more short pieces than novels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, the 2016 Gretna Writing Project Institute was time well spent. The 2016 participants have been encouraging their professional peers to take the leap and join next year’s institute. Hopefully we will see even more departments working to incorporate more writing into their lives and courses as they are increasingly represented in this powerful program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;Docs/2016gwpanthology.pdf&quot; class=&quot;wdn-button wdn-button-triad&quot;&gt;Download the anthology&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jennifer Long  |  Nebraska Writing Project&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Monday, January 9, 2017 - 09:24</pubDate>
 <dc:creator />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">77980</guid>
  </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
